holland.com 2019-12-03

# Privacy and cookie statement - Holland.com

_This privacy and cookie statement was changed most recently on: 15 October 2019               _

Your privacy is very important to NBTC Holland Marketing. We therefore comply with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

This means that we:

  *  **Lay down our purposes clearly** before we process your personal data, via this privacy and cookie statement;

  *  **Store as little personal data as possible** and only those data that are needed for our purposes;

  *  **Expressly request consent** for the processing of your personal data, should consent be mandatory;

  *  **Implement the necessary security measures** to protect your personal data. We impose these obligations also on parties that process personal data on our behalf;

  *  **Respect your rights** , such as the right to inspect, correct or delete your personal data processed by us.

####  **Processing personal data**

We explain in this privacy and cookie statement what we do with information we find out about you in providing our services and on our web page. You provide us with various types of personal data concerning yourself when you use one of our services. It is indicated per subject what data we obtain from you and for how long we retain these data, for which purpose this happens and on what basis. If you have questions or if you would like to know exactly what information we keep about you, please contact NBTC Holland Marketing via the details provided at the end of this statement.

####  **Our services** ****

Holland.com is the starting point when preparing for your trip to the Netherlands. The website offers more than 10,000 articles with information concerning tourist destinations in our country. In order to be able to provide you with personalized content, we collect your IP address to be able to use retargeting cookies. For more information concerning this processing of personal data, please refer to the information in the cookie table provided further on in this statement.

 _Tickets  
_ Holland.com cooperates with reputable partners to make your holiday unforgettable. We offer a broad range of hotels, holiday homes and other accommodation. You can also turn to us for a complete bicycle holiday or admission tickets for attractions and museums. You conclude an agreement with the relevant partner when booking accommodation and/or a ticket. We refer you to the privacy statements of the partners in question for more information on how they handle your personal data.

####  **Contact** ****

You can contact NBTC Holland Marketing, namely by telephone, by post or by e-mail. We use the following personal data for this purpose ****

  * Name and address details;

  * Company name (optional);

  * E-mail address;

  * Telephone number;

  * Any information you yourself provide as content of a message or conversation.

We require these data to handle your contact request, because you requested us to contact you. We retain this information until we consider that you are satisfied with our response and for three months thereafter. This will allow us to consult the information easily in case of follow-up questions. It also allows us to train our customer service employees to become even better. If the moment of contact leads to an agreement, we will retain those data for as long as that agreement lasts.

####  **Newsletter**

We have a newsletter of irregular frequency and you will only be added to the list of subscribers with your consent. You can read press releases and inspirational articles in the newsletter. We use your name, e-mail address and (any) company name for this purpose. We do so on the basis of your consent. We retain this information until you cancel the subscription. You can terminate the subscription to the newsletter at any time. Every newsletter includes an unsubscribe link.

#### Use of images 

We use images to show you what Holland looks like. If you have published images on Instagram, we may ask your permission to use your images on our social media channels as well as in newsletters and reports. If you grant permission, we will process the following (personal) information:

  * Your Instagram username;
  * Any information you yourself provide as content of a post;
  * Image material

We save this information until we no longer need the image material for our marketing purposes, up to a maximum of five years. You can withdraw permission at any time and we will remove your image material as soon as possible. To this end, you may contact us. You can find our contact details at the end of this privacy and cookie statement. ****

####  **Provision to third parties**

We may provide your personal data to other companies or institutions, because:

  * We engaged them to process certain data;

  * We show Google and Facebook advertisements to users of this website in cooperation with third parties;

  * This is necessary in order to perform the agreement with you;

  * The proper performance of our activities within the context of the existing work and other relations;

  * You consent thereto; 

  * To look after our (joint) interests, unless your personal interest or fundamental rights and freedoms prevail over this interest;

  * We are obliged by law to do so (for example if this is demanded by the police in the case of suspicion of a crime).

The following third parties process your personal data:

  * Our cookie service providers (see below); 

  * Our IT service providers;

  * Our payment service provider;

  * Advertising suppliers;

  * Marketing companies

  * External parties that handle bookings for us;

  * Tour operators;

  * Hotels and accommodation;

  * Our partners and intermediaries.

We collaborate with third parties with registered offices outside the European Economic Area. One of the marketing companies (CrowdRiff) with which we collaborate is registered in Canada. Canada is classified as third country with an adequate level of protection, which means that Canada maintains a suitable level of data protection. 

#### **Cookies**

We use cookies on our website. A cookie is a simple, small file that is sent together with pages of this website and that are stored on the hard drive of your device by your browser. The information stored therein can be sent back again to our servers in case of a subsequent visit. 

Cookie; Entity; guarantees | Category | Type | Retention period | Purpose  
---|---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics - Google LLC, America, [PrivacyShield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI "https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI"), [Privacy statement](https://policies.google.com/privacy "https://policies.google.com/privacy") | Analytical | Https-cookie | At most 2 years | Cookies are placed to gain insight into visitor behavior and to improve the user experience on the basis thereof. We have set these cookies in a privacy-sensitive manner. This means that we: - have concluded a processing agreement with Google; - give Google only masked IP addresses; - do not share any other data with Google; and - we do not use other Google services combined with analytics.   
Google TagManager - Google LLC, America, [PrivacyShield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI "https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI"), [Privacy statement](https://policies.google.com/privacy "https://policies.google.com/privacy") | Functional | Https-cookie | Session | Manages tags on the website so that they are indexed correctly.  
Google DoubleClick, Google Audiences - Google LLC, America, [PrivacyShield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI "https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI"), [Privacy statement](https://policies.google.com/privacy "https://policies.google.com/privacy") | Advertisement | Https-cookie | At most 6 months | Cookies are used to register actions of the website visitors to the website after viewing/clicking on advertisements. The purpose is to measure effectiveness and display personalized advertisements. Cookies from GA Audiences are used to track visitors based on their online website behavior. This means that click behavior is registered in order to measure effectiveness and offer website visitors personalized content.  
Facebook Connect - Facebook America, [Privacy statement](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation "https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation"), [PrivacyShield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC "https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC") | Advertisement | Http-cookie/ pixel tracker | At most 3 months | Cookies are used to make Facebook advertisement options possible. Registers click behavior and website visits. Cookies register a unique ID for the purpose of recognizing returning devices. The purpose of this is targeted advertising and personalized advertising.  
Hotjar - Hotjar Malta, [Privacy statement](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/terms-of-service "https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/terms-of-service") | Analytical | Http-cookie | At most 1 year | Hotjar is a technological service that helps us better understand the experience of our users; how much time they spend on which page, what links they decide to click, what users do and do not enjoy etc. This enables us to improve our website using user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data regarding the behavior of our users and their devices (in particular the IP addresses of devices (laid down and stored only in anonymized format), screen resolution of the device, device type (unique device ID's), browser information, geographic location (only at country level), preferred language for displaying our website). This functionality is not engaged until you consent to the placement of cookies.   
Cloudflare - Cloudflare America, [PrivacyShield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnZKAA0&status=Active "https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnZKAA0&status=Active"), [Privacy statement](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/?utm_referrer=https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170156-What-does-the-CloudFlare-cfduid-cookie-do- "https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/?utm_referrer=https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170156-What-does-the-CloudFlare-cfduid-cookie-do-") | Functional | Http-cookie | Session | The Cloudflare content network uses cookies to identified trusted web traffic.  
Booking.com - Booking.com The Netherlands, [Privacy statement](https://www.booking.com/content/privacy.nl.html "https://www.booking.com/content/privacy.nl.html") | Advertisement | Http-cookie | At most 1 year | Visitors can perform bookings on our website via our partners. Booking.com is one of our partners. Cookies from our partner Booking.com enable booking functionalities. We receive a fee for all bookings on booking.com generated by referral traffic from Holland.com.  
BlueConic Plugin - Blueconic America, [Privacy statement](https://www.blueconic.com/privacy-policy/ "https://www.blueconic.com/privacy-policy/"), [PrivacyShield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GokXAAS&status=Active "https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GokXAAS&status=Active") | Advertisement | Http-cookie | At most 2 years | BlueConic is a supplier of technologies for profiling website visitors for targeted marketing purposes, which is established in the US and the Netherlands. BlueConic cookies are used to gain insight into the use of our website, and to improve this on the basis of these insights and to increase ease of use. This plugin makes it possible to collect information concerning the website visitor and the actual visit.  
Miscellaneous: First-party cookies with strictly functional purposes.  | Functional | Http-cookie | At most 2 years | Cookies that enable the necessary functionalities of the website, such as loading and displaying fonts. Makes it possible to show the cookie banner and to have it operate, but also to secure the website.  
  
We display a notice explaining cookies when you visit the website for the first time. In this connection, we will ask for your consent to use cookies in so far as we are obliged to do so.

We have made arrangements with other companies that place cookies concerning the use of the cookies. Nevertheless, we do not have full control over what they do with the cookies. You should therefore also read their privacy statements.

####  **Social media** ****

Our website includes social media buttons. These buttons allow you to decide to indicate via your own social media account in respect of these services that you are interested in our products and services or to share our page with your network. This will then be visible to the visitors to your personal social media website page. If you click on a social media button, the relevant service may place one or more cookies for the purpose of recognizing you. The privacy statement of the relevant service applies to the use of such social media websites:

  * [Twitter privacy statement](https://twitter.com/privacy "https://twitter.com/privacy");

  * [Instagram privacy statement](https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388 "https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388");

  * [YouTube privacy statement](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=nl "https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=nl");

  * [Pinterest privacy statement](https://policy.pinterest.com/nl/privacy-policy "https://policy.pinterest.com/nl/privacy-policy").

The information is transferred to and by Facebook and LinkedIn and stored on servers in the United States. LinkedIn and Facebook state that they comply with the Privacy Shield principles and are affiliated with the Privacy Shield program of the American Department of Commerce. This means that an appropriate level of protection for the processing of any personal data applies.

####  **Switching cookies on and off**

You can switch off the placement of cookies via your browser, but this may mean that some options of our website no longer work properly. You can find more information about switching cookies on and off and about the removal of cookies in the instructions and/or with the aid of the Help function of your browser.

####  **Security**

Securing your personal data is very important to us. We ensure that your data are secured properly with us. We adjust the security continuously and look out carefully for what could go wrong. 

#### **Changes to this privacy and cookie statement** ****

Naturally, we have to adjust the privacy and cookie statement in case our website or one of our services changes. You should therefore always be aware of the date set out above and check for new versions on a regular basis.

####  **Your rights**

You can always contact us if you have questions or if you would like to know which personal data we hold in respect of you. See the contact details below.

You have the following rights:

  *  **Right to inspect** : you have the right to inspect the personal data we process in respect of you.

  *  **Right to rectification:** you have the right to correct or supplement the personal data we process in respect of you if these are incorrect or incomplete.

  *  **Right to withdraw your consent** : you can always easily withdraw your consent. 

  * **Right to object** : you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data.

  *  **Right to delete** : you have the right to request us to delete your personal data.

  *  **Right to data portability** : if this is possible in a technical sense, you have the right to have the personal data we process in respect of you transferred to a third party.

  *  **Right to limit the processing** : you have the right to request that the processing of your personal data be limited, temporarily or otherwise, which means that we process less of your personal data.

We may ask you to identify yourself in connection with your request. We request data in this connection in order to be certain that you are the right person to whom the personal data belong. Depending on the information we have in respect of you, we may ask you to do so by enclosing a copy of a valid identity document. It is important that your Citizens Service Number and passport photo are blocked out.

We will comply with your request within 30 days in principle. However, this term may be extended for reasons related to the specific rights of data subjects or the complexity of the request. We will inform you on time if we extend this term.

####  **Submitting complaints**

If you consider that we are not helping you properly, you have the right to submit a complaint to the privacy supervisor. This authority is called the [Dutch Data Protection Authority](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/nl/zelf-doen/privacyrechten/klacht-indienen-bij-de-ap "https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/nl/zelf-doen/privacyrechten/klacht-indienen-bij-de-ap") in the Netherlands.

####  **Contact and business details** ****

Stichting NBTC Holland Marketing  
Pr. Catharina-Amaliastraat 5  
2496XD in The Hague  
Website: [https://www.holland.com](https://www.holland.com/ "https://www.holland.com")  
E-mail address: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3444465d4255574d745c5b5858555a501a575b59 "mailto:privacy@holland.com")  
Telephone number: +31 70-3705705  
Ch. of Comm. number: 27192610

You can adjust your privacy preferences by going to privacy settings.
